<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SBI FAIR on SBI-FAIR</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in SBI FAIR on SBI-FAIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Links</title><link>/docs/notes/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/links/</guid><description>Overall Project Links
Google-group: https://groups.google.com/g/sbi-fair Website: https://sbi-fair.github.io/ Publications: https://sbi-fair.github.io/docs/publications/ The directory from proposal writing: DOE_FAIR2020-Surrogates Directory for this proposal: Afteraward Meeting Summaries Report:: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cqMOkV9Cag6EB6HI6fR20gwhVwUeG5yijtJ3aEW0Crs</description></item><item><title>AutoPhaseNN: unsupervised physics-aware deep learning of 3D nanoscale Bragg coherent diffraction imaging</title><link>/docs/surrogates/autophasenn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/autophasenn/</guid><description>Metadata Model autophasenn.json
Datasets autoPhaseNN_aicdi.json
Adapted from Yao, Y. et. al 1 under CC-BY 2
AutoPhaseNN 1, a physics-aware unsupervised deep convolutional neural network (CNN) that learns to solve the phase problem without ever being shown real space images of the sample amplitude or phase. By incorporating the physics of the X-ray scattering into the network design and training, AutoPhaseNN learns to predict both the amplitude and phase of the sample given the measured diffraction intensity alone.</description></item><item><title>Calorimeter surrogates</title><link>/docs/surrogates/calorimeter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/calorimeter/</guid><description>Overview The Kaggle calorimeter challenge uses generative AI to produce a surrogate for the Monte Carlo calculation of a calorimeter response to an incident particle (ATLAS data at LHC calculated with GEANT4). Variational Auto Encoders, GANs, Normalizing Flows, and Diffusion Models. We also have a surrogate using a Quantum Computer (DWAVE) annealer to generate random samples. We have identified four different surrogates that are available openly from Kaggle and later submissions.</description></item><item><title>Virtual tissue</title><link>/docs/surrogates/virtualtissue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/virtualtissue/</guid><description>Overview Neural networks (NNs) have been demonstrated to be a viable alternative to traditional direct numerical evaluation algorithms, with the potential to accelerate computational time by several orders of magnitude. In the present paper we study the use of encoder-decoder convolutional neural network (CNN) algorithms as surrogates for steady-state diffusion solvers. The construction of such surrogates requires the selection of an appropriate task, network architecture, training set structure and size, loss function, and training algorithm hyperparameters.</description></item><item><title>Cosmoflow</title><link>/docs/surrogates/cosmoflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/cosmoflow/</guid><description>Metadata Model cosmoflow.json
Datasets
cosmoUniverse_2019_05_4parE_tf_v2.json
cosmoUniverse_2019_05_4parE_tf_v2_mini.json
Overview This application is based on the original CosmoFlow paper presented at SC18 and continued by the ExaLearn project, and adopted as a benchmark in the MLPerf HPC suite. It involves training a 3D convolutional neural network on N-body cosmology simulation data to predict physical parameters of the universe. The reference implementation for MLPerf HPC v0.5 CosmoFlow uses TensorFlow with the Keras API and Horovod for data-parallel distributed training.</description></item><item><title>Fully ionized plasma fluid model closures</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ionized-plasma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ionized-plasma/</guid><description>Fully ionized plasma fluid model closures (Argonne):1 The closure problem in fluid modeling is a well-known challenge to modelers aiming to accurately describe their system of interest. Analytic formulations in a wide range of regimes exist but a practical, generalized fluid closure for magnetized plasmas remains an elusive goal. There are scenarios where complex physics prevents a simple closure being assumed, and the question as to what closure to employ has a non-trivial answer.</description></item><item><title>Ions in nanoconfinement</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ions-in-nanoconfinement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ions-in-nanoconfinement/</guid><description>Metadata Model nanoconfinement.json
Datasets nanoconfinement.json
This application 1 2 3 studies ionic structure in electrolyte solutions in nanochannels with planar uncharged surfaces and can use multiple molecular dynamics (MD) codes including LAMMPS 4 which run on HPC supercomputers with OpenMP and MPI parallelization.
A dense neural-net (NN) was used to learn 150 final state characteristics based on the input of 5 parameters with typical results shown in fig. 2(b) with the NN results for three important densities tracking well the MD simulation results for a wide range of unseen input system parameters.</description></item><item><title>Metadata Subgroup</title><link>/docs/subgroups/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/subgroups/metadata/</guid><description>This subgroup is lead but University of Tennessee, Knoxville.
Schema Development As part of the logging, reporting activities, this subgroup is tasked to create appropriate schema to follow the FAIR principles. Below is a general overview of the major hierarchy of data that needs to be recorded for reproducibility.
Hardware specifications Compute: CPUs, Accelerators Memory: caches, NUMA Network: on-node CPU and accelerator coherency, NIC and off-node switches Peripherals Storage: primary (SSD), secondary (HDD), tertiary (RAID/remote) Firmware: ID/release date Software stack Compiler: GCC, Clang, vendor AI framework: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, MxNet Tensor backend: JAX, TVM Runtime: JVM, OpenMP, CUDA Messaging API: MPI, NCCL, RCCL OS: Linux Container: Singularity, Docker, CharlieCloud Input data Data sets (version, size) Image: MNIST digits/fashion, CIFAR 10/100, ImageNet, VGG Language: Transformer Science: instrument, simulation Annotations Model data Release date, ID, repo/branch/tag/hash, URL Output data Performance rate: training, inference Power draw: training, inference Energy consumption Convergence: epochs Accuracy, recall</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>/docs/team/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/team/team/</guid><description> Geoffrey Fox, Indiana University (Principal Investigator) Vikram Jadhao, Indiana University (Co-Investigator) Gregor von Laszewski, Indiana University (Co-Investigator), laszewski@gmail.com, https://laszewski.github.io Rick Stevens, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Peter Beckman, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Kamil Iskra, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Min Si, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Jack Dongarra, University of Tennessee, Knoxville (Co-Investigator) Piotr Luszczek, University of Tennessee, Knoxville (Co-Investigator) Shantenu Jha, Rutgers University (Co-Investigator)</description></item><item><title>Molecule docking</title><link>/docs/surrogates/molecule-docking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/molecule-docking/</guid><description>Molecule docking: Docking small molecules to a protein’s binding site is often one of the first steps for virtual screening 1. Although many open-source and commercial packages exist for docking, AI approaches can be equally powerful (and computationally more efficient) for docking studies 2. Utilizing advances in control from reinforcement learning (RL), Argonne researchers trained an agent to drive the docking of a rigid ligand into a flexible protein pocket. The RL agent treats the ligand as a rigid body to which it can move through affine transformations along the protein.</description></item><item><title>miniWeatherML</title><link>/docs/surrogates/miniweatherml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/miniweatherml/</guid><description>Metadata Model miniWeatherML.json
Datasets miniWeatherML.json
Overview MiniWeatherML is a playground for learning and developing Machine Learning (ML) surrogate models and workflows. It is based on a simplified weather model simulating flows such as supercells that are realistic enough to be challenging and simple enough for rapid prototyping in:
Data generation and curation Machine Learning model training ML model deployment and analysis End-to-end workflows 12
References https://github.com/mrnorman/miniWeatherML&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
https://github.com/mrnorman/miniWeatherML/wiki&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>cloudmesh</title><link>/docs/software/cloudmesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/software/cloudmesh/</guid><description>Overview Cloudmesh allows the creation of an extensible commandline and commandshell tool based internally on a number of python APIs that can be loaded conveniently through plugins.
Plugins useful for this effort include
cloudmesh-vpn1 &amp;ndash; a convenient way to configure VPN cloudmesh-common2 &amp;ndash; useful common libraries including a StopWatch for benchmarking cloudmesh-cmd53 &amp;ndash; a plugin manager that allows plugins to be integrated as commandline tool or command shell cloudmesh-ee4 &amp;ndash; A pluging to create AI grid searchs using LSF and SLURM jobs cloudmesh-cc5 &amp;ndash; A plugin to allow benchmarks to be run in coordination on heterogeneous compute resources and multiple clusters cloudmesh-apptainer6 &amp;ndash; mangae apptainers via a Python API Cloudmesh has over 100 plugins coordinated at http://github.</description></item><item><title>OSMI</title><link>/docs/surrogates/osmi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/osmi/</guid><description>Overview We explore the relationship between certain network configurations and the performance of distributed Machine Learning systems. We build upon the Open Surrogate Model Inference (OSMI) Benchmark, a distributed inference benchmark for analyzing the performance of machine-learned surrogate models developed by Wes Brewer et. Al. We focus on analyzing distributed machine-learning systems, via machine-learned surrogate models, across varied hardware environments. By deploying the OSMI Benchmark on platforms like Rivanna HPC, WSL, and Ubuntu, we offer a comprehensive study of system performance under different configurations.</description></item><item><title>sabath</title><link>/docs/software/sabath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/software/sabath/</guid><description>Introduction SABATH provides benchmarking infrastructure for evaluating scientific ML/AI models. It contains support for scientific machine learning surrogates from external repositories such as SciML-Bench.
The software dependences are explicitly exposed in the surrogate model definition, which allows the use of advanced optimization, communication, and hardware features. For example, distributed, multi-GPU training may be enabled with Horovod. Surrogate models may be implemented using TensorFlow, PyTorch, or MXNET frameworks.
Models Models are collected so far at</description></item><item><title>Particle dynamics</title><link>/docs/surrogates/particle-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/particle-dynamics/</guid><description>Recurrent Neural Nets as a Particle Dynamics Integrator
The second IU initial application shows a rather different type of surrogate and illustrates an SBI goal to collect benchmarks covering a range of surrogate designs. Molecular dynamics simulations rely on numerical integrators such as Verlet to solve Newton&amp;rsquo;s equations of motion. Using a sufficiently small time step to avoid discretization errors, Verlet integrators generate a trajectory of particle positions as solutions to the equations of motions.</description></item><item><title>Performance Surrogate</title><link>/docs/surrogates/performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/performance/</guid><description>Overview Please contact Piotre
References</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 02-05-2024</title><link>/docs/notes/2024-02-05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2024-02-05/</guid><description>Notes https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E-eP45yqDofctCfzCb4QWiDmfYwXvXKGde6ex1c1fWg/edit Virginia Virginia started a list of surrogates that would help prepare any poster necessary https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LonfbydMlQyLBv5vh8tjATv9BxdN7GmjuU8RFyuK5aw/edit#slide=id.g2acfd0f37ff_1_151
Virginia status is https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LonfbydMlQyLBv5vh8tjATv9BxdN7GmjuU8RFyuK5aw/edit#slide=id.g2acfd0f37ff_1_100 and other slides here plus https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fqKphJlK4Q_zE1wIAxHs73c4LHFjAKzjXIiMSS_opnw/edit?usp=sharing
Web page https://sbi-fair.github.io/
Rutgers ASCR-PI-Meeting-Feb-2024-Rutgers
Indiana Indiana has 2 surrogates. Ions in nano confinement.This code allows users to simulate ions confined between material surfaces that are nanometers apart, and extract the associated ionic structure. time evolution: GitHub: Code for our paper &amp;ldquo;Simulating Molecular Dynamics with Large Timesteps using Recurrent Neural Networks&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 01-08-2024</title><link>/docs/notes/2024-01-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2024-01-08/</guid><description>Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Piotr Luszczek, Shantenu Jha
Apologies Vikram Jadhao
Shantenu described the background to the PI meeting for ASCR in February that was modeled on successful SCIDAC-wide meetings. It is not clear if sessions will be plenary or organized around Program manager portfolios. Virginia started a list of surrogates that would help prepare any poster necessary https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LonfbydMlQyLBv5vh8tjATv9BxdN7GmjuU8RFyuK5aw/edit#slide=id.g2acfd0f37ff_1_151 Argonne would add work on I/O, compression, and second-order methods.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10-30-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-10-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-10-30/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR October 30 2023, Meeting
Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Piotr Luszczek, Vikram Jadhao,** **Shantenu Jha, Margaret Lentz
AI for Science report AI for Science, Energy, and Security Report | Argonne National Laboratory ASCAC Advanced Scientific Comput&amp;hellip; | U.S. DOE Office of Science(SC) Hal Finkel’s (Director Research ASCR Advanced Scientific Computing talk ASCR Research Priorities is important Anticipated Solicitations in FY 2024 Compared to FY 2023, expect a smaller number of larger, more-broadly-scoped solicitations driving innovation across ASCR’s research community.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 09-25-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-09-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-09-25/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR September 25 2023, Meeting
Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Piotr Luszczek, Vikram Jadhao
Apologies: Shantenu Jha, Kamil Iskra, Margaret Lentz
Virginia
**Presentation ** Repository Specific environments are needed for different models Requirements.txt Different hardware support Copy MLCommons approach MLCube as a target Tools to generate targets Release before supercomputing Add MLCommons benchmarks Separate repositories in version 2 Argonne
Finished the contract but will, of course, complete their papers.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 08-25-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-08-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-08-25/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR August 28 2023, Meeting
Monday, September 25, 2023, https://virginia.zoom.us/my/gc.fox Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Kamil Iskra,, Baixi Sun. Piotr Luszczek,
Apologies: Shantenu Jha, Vikram Jadhao, Margaret Lentz (Rutgers and Indiana not presented)
Virginia
SABATH extensions OSMIBench improved Experiment Executor added in Cloudmesh Argonne surrogates supported Argonne
Baixi presented their new work SOLAR paper with artifacts submitted The communication bottleneck in the second order method K-FAC addressed with compression and sparsification methods with SSO Framework Tennessee</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 07-31-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-07-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-07-31/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR July 31 2023, Meeting
Monday, August 28, 2023, https://virginia.zoom.us/my/gc.fox Monday, September 25, 2023, https://virginia.zoom.us/my/gc.fox Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Piotr Luszczek, Shantenu Jha
Apologies: Vikram Jadhao,
Virginia
Geoffrey presented the Virginia Update https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/132erkV49Lgd0ZFx-AtNWJPRwTrxc480m-rU6jmvMmYA/edit?usp=sharing, which also included Indiana (see below) Good progress with Argonne Surrogates We have added PtychoNN to SABATH, and we have run AutoPhaseNN on Rivanna We reviewed other surrogates from Virginia including OSMIBench and a new Calorimeter simulation We are working well with Tennessee on SABATH Gregor finished with a little study on use of Rivanna &amp;ndash; the Virginia Supercomputer Indiana</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 06-26-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-06-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-06-26/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR June 26, 2023, Meeting
**Present: **Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Piotr Luszczek, Shantenu Jha, Margaret Lentz
Virginia
This was presented by Geoffrey He described work on new surrogates, including LHC Calorimeter, Epidemiology, Extended virtual tissue, and Earthquake He described work on the repository and SABATH This involved two existing AI models CloudMask and OSMIBench Shantenu Jha asked about the number of inferences per second.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 05-29-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-05-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-05-29/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR May 29, 2023, Meeting
Present: Geoffrey Fox, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Piotr Luszczek,
Virginia
Comment on Surrogates produced by generative methods versus those that map particular inputs to particular outputs. In examples like experimental physics apparatus simulations, you only need output and not input. Methods need to sample output data space correctly. Geoffrey also described earlier experiences using second-order methods and least squares/maximum likelihood optimizations for physics data analysis.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 04-03-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-04-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-04-03/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR April 3 2023, Meeting
Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Piotr Luszczek, Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Margaret Lentz (DOE),
Regrets: Shantenu Jha
**DOE **had no major announcements but reminded us of links
US Department of Energy Office of Science ASCR Funding Opportunities | U.S. DOE Office of Science (SC) Also noted that No Cost extensions were needed six months before the official end due to the heavy load at the DOE Chicago office.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 02-27-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-02-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-02-27/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR February 27 2023, Meeting
**Present: **Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Gregor von Laszewski, Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao,
We discussed modifying our simple summary describing the status and plans for the project to add a discussion of the timeline. Virginia did theirs as an example on slide 2.
Indiana
Vikram discussed recent activity, responding to referee comments on their recent paper.
Virginia
Geoffrey noted two new surrogates: A diffusion surrogate https://arxiv.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 01-30-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-01-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-01-30/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR January 2, 9, and 30 2023, Meetings
January 2 2023:
**Present: **Deborah Penchoff, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Gregor von Laszewski
We discussed producing a simple summary (roughly one slide per institution) describing the status and plans for the project. Virginia, UTK, and Rutgers made a draft which will be expanded before our January 30 meeting with Margaret. These should mention inter-institution collaborations. We continued on January 9</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 01-05-2023</title><link>/docs/notes/2023-01-05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2023-01-05/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR May 1, 2023, Meeting
Present: Geoffrey Fox, Gregor von Laszewski, Przemek Porebski, Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Piotr Luszczek,
Regrets: Shantenu Jha
Virginia Geoffrey noted continued progress with the new Virtual Tissue surrogate using UNet and periodic boundary conditions. Interesting that UNet mimics multigrid PDE methods. Przemyslaw still disentangling from other work but will start very soon. Several (50 in 2 weeks) undergraduate and incoming graduate student research requests.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 11-28-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-11-28/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR November 28, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Deborah Penchoff, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Gregor von Laszewski and Margaret Lentz from DOE
Preparations/drafts: Nov 28 2022 DOE Project Review Preparations
Actually delivered presentations are has on the first slide links to individual presentations in the order
Virginia Tennessee Argonne Rutgers Indiana Margaret emphasized the need for continued interaction and we scheduled the next meeting with Margaret on January 30, 2023.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10-31-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-10-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-10-31/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR October 31, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Peter Beckman, Deborah Penchoff, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Virginia
Geoffrey discussed
The transfer of the DOE grant is completed The Tsunami surrogate (see last meeting) is finished while the diffusion-based surrogate is still being finalized Rough draft of the diffusion model for cell simulations GENERALIZATION AND TRANSFER LEARNING IN A DEEP DIFFUSION SURROGATE FOR MECHANISTIC REAL-WORLD SIMULATIONS.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 09-26-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-09-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-09-26/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR September 26, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Deborah Penchoff, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun. Vikram Jadhao, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Virginia
Geoffrey discussed
The transfer of the DOE grant is still making progress He noted two nearly completed new surrogates paper on Tsunami simulation surrogates entitled “Forecasting tsunami inundation with convolutional neural networks for a potential Cascadia Subduction Zone rupture” Rough draft of the diffusion model for cell simulations GENERALIZATION AND TRANSFER LEARNING IN A DEEP DIFFUSION SURROGATE FOR MECHANISTIC REAL-WORLD SIMULATIONS.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 08-15-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-08-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-08-15/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR August 15, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Xiaodong Yu, Deborah Penchoff, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun.
Apologies Vikram Jadhao,
Updates
Virginia
Geoffrey discussed
The transfer of the DOE grant is making progress He is continuing his study of Foundation models by collecting common applications using similar deep learning systems He summarized the MLCommons status answering some questions noting that MLCommons collects surrogates and non-surrogate benchmarks Geoffrey will send Shantenu notice about MLCommons meetings Gregor</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 06-27-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-06-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-06-27/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR June 27, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Deborah Penchoff, Vikram Jadhao, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Virginia
Foundation Models &amp;ndash; collect surrogates Need a group DOE report. Use last year&amp;rsquo;s approach with a common response initialized by Piotr https://docs.google.com/document/d/19cbBj2IMIMa_HUPAUaREy3zRYBQfEoS5hCmM7wyU48c/edit?usp=sharing Note plans went a bit different as due to transfer Indiana and Virginia were not asked for annual reports Tennessee
SABATH software MLCommons Paper ISC Piotr Luszczek went and did not get Covid.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 05-23-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-05-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-05-23/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR May 23, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Deborah Penchoff, Vikram Jadhao, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Xiaodong Yu, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Virginia
Geoffrey described substantial progress with Science working group of MLCommons which should have reached first base on June 1 at an ISC BOF The diffusion equation surrogate work with Javier Toledo and James Glazier is being written up. He also commented on Argonne shuffling performance and use of Big Data collective shuffle primitives that work on disk and memory.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 04-25-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-04-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-04-25/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR April 25, 2022, Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Deborah Penchoff, Vikram Jadhao, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Xiaodong Yu, Piotr Luszczek, Cade Brown, Baixi Sun, Jack Dongarra
Updates
Virginia
Discussed continued work on diffusion surrogate with Glazier and Javier Toledo (Edmonton) Discussed Fusion surrogate benchmark from Lawrence Livermore Tennessee
Cade Brown presented an update Discussed Sentinel 3 benchmark based on UK Cloudmask from MLCommons Then discussed FAIR Benchmark platform SLIP which is has been extended to become SABATH Described report structure Model format - how universal is this Has done UK cloudmask and looked at TEvol (2 MLCommons benchmarks) Deal with Jupyter notebooks with nbconvert Add callbacks to model.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 03-19-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-03-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-03-19/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR March 19, 2022, Meeting Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Shantenu Jha, Geoffrey Fox, Xiaodong Yu, Piotr Luszczek, Cade Brown, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski Updates
Rutgers
A postdoc left unexpectedly and so the surrogate classification work was delayed. The integration of Rutgers software into Vikram’s work is proceeding and will be tested with a Summit allocation.
Indiana
Vikram discussed a surrogate paper accepted by Machine Learning: Science and Technology journal https://doi.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 02-14-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-02-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-02-14/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR February 14 2022 Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Geoffrey Fox, Deborah Penchoff, Xiaodong Yu, Piotr Luszczek, Cade Brown, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski Updates
Tennessee
A new team member Cade Brown gave a fascinating talk CadeBrown-notes-SBI_Schema. Cade Brown is a new ICL student tasked with designing a schema and tooling for installing, running, and benchmarking ML models. He showed examples using MLCommons Science benchmarks CloudMask and STEMDL.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 01-10-2022</title><link>/docs/notes/2022-01-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2022-01-10/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR January 10 2022 Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Geoffrey Fox, Deborah Penchoff, Xiaodong Yu, Jack Dongarra, Shantenu Jha, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Tennessee
Piotr reported UTK’s continued progress with the FAIR technology in his presentation with a discussion of the ontology needed for SciML and extensions to MLCommons. The choice of YAML versus XML and TOML was discussed. There was a discussion between Piotr and Gregor about that indicated that the YAML format is not sufficient to encode the surrogate and the hardware used for it.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 10-21-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-10-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-10-21/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR October 25 2021 Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Geoffrey Fox, Deborah Penchoff, Xiaodong Yu, Jack Dongarra, Shantenu Jha, Piotr Luszczek, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Tennessee
Piotr reported that paper submitted to IPDPS; and metadata (FAIR) work is continuing
Virginia
Geoffrey has summarized 4 possible MLCommons Science Datasets that could be useful for FAIR studies. See recent Argonne preprint
Indiana
Vikram Jadhao described his new surrogate paper [2110.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 09-27-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-09-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-09-27/</guid><description>Minutes of SBI-FAIR September 27 2021 Meeting
Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Geoffrey Fox, Deborah Penchoff, Xiaodong Yu, Jack Dongarra, Shantenu Jha, Piotr Luszczek, Pete Beckman, Baixi Sun, Gregor von Laszewski
Updates
Indiana/Virginia
Vikram has a new surrogate and is finalizing a paper on it. He will talk to Shantenu soon.
Rutgers
Shantenu affected by hurricane
Developing 3 layer simulations with surrogate at each level ML driven HPC motifs/patterns identified in research to be reported at November meeting DeepDriveMD ensemble is one example climate science simulations gives surrogates that select best simulation Link with observation link seen in climate, materials and biomolecular science University of Tennessee</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 08-30-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-08-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-08-30/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting August 30, 2021
Present: Kamil Iskra, Vikram Jadhao, Geoffrey Fox, Deborah Penchoff, Xiaodong Yu, Jack Dongarra, Shantenu Jha, Piotr Luszczek, Pete Beckman, Baixi Sun
Updates
Rutgers: Progress with recruiting problems. Highlighted a new paper https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.8b00839 on molecular benchmarks from Benevolent AI GuacaMol: Benchmarking Models for De Novo Molecular Design. Peter Coveney Company in London Tennessee continues work on the performance surrogate model. Tune hyperparameters. Build from small runs.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 07-26-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-07-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-07-26/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting July 26, 2021
Shantenu led a discussion of surrogates noting his work was delayed by a loss of a postdoc. Shantenu divided Surrogates into 3 areas
**MLinHPC **as in Climate in Oxford paper [2001.08055] Building high accuracy emulators for scientific simulations with deep neural architecture search giving speedups over a billion but there are some curious features of this work. Directly replace full simulation but also can calculate potentials as in DeepMD https://arxiv.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 06-29-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-06-29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-06-29/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting June 29, 2021
Annual Report
This meeting focussed on getting the final version of the DOE annual report which was submitted the following day by each institution.
Next Meeting
Our meetings are 1 pm Eastern on the 4th Monday of each month
This implies Monday, July 25, 1 pm at zoom https://iu.zoom.us/j/2301429329
In the July meeting, Shantenu Jha will lead a discussion of surrogates, postponed from June</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 05-24-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-05-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-05-24/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting May 24, 2021
Links for Today’s Meeting
Powerpoint of Argonne Talk 2021-05-SBI-ANL.pptx
PDF of Argonne Talk 2021-05-SBI-ANL.pdf
Present
Argonne: Min Si, Xiaodong Yu
**Indiana: **Geoffrey Fox, Vikram Jadhao, Gregor von Laszewski
Rutgers: Shantenu Jha
UTK: Jack Dongarra, Piotr Luszczek
Argonne Presentation
Xiaodong Yu’s described 3 surrogates being developed at Argonne
Application 1 **PtychoNN: Ptychographic Imaging Reconstruction phase reconstruction **
Here the challenge is to determine phases from Xray scattering data with paper.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 04-19-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-04-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-04-19/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting April 19, 2021
Links for Today’s Meeting
Indiana Update plus Overall Project Remarks SBI-Meeting-IU-April19-2021 Tennessee Update Presentation sbi20210419.pdf Updates
Argonne postponed their update to the next meeting and the other 3 sites gave updates. Indiana discussed SciMLBench from the UK with its first release and the related MLCommons Science benchmarking. With surrogates, Jadhao will work on the nanoengineering one in the Fall and Fox completed an initial study of a virtual tissue surrogate [2102.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 03-23-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-03-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-03-23/</guid><description>Minutes of Meeting March 23 2021
Links for Today’s Meeting
Argonne Update Presentation SBI- ANL-202103-Updates Argonne Surrogate Application SBI-ANL-202103-Ptycho-Surrogate.pptx Tennessee Update Presentation SBI @ UTK 2k21 Indiana University Update Presentation SBI-Meeting-IU-Mar23-2021 Christine Kirkpatrick’s MLCommons Science working group talk on FAIR Metadata mlcommons_fair_0221.pptx Compilation of MLCommons logged metadata Logging Info MLCommons The 4 sites all gave updates with presentations listed above.
Indiana largely discussed work with MLCommons Science research working group</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 02-20-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-02-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-02-20/</guid><description>University of Tennessee Knoxville Deborah Penchoff joining the team UTK Schema MLFlow &amp;ndash; reproducibility Is training repeatable Need to have a group on this UTK have their own surrogates science and performance Storage Uq Hardware Rutgers University Performance of surrogates What does it mean Gordon bell prizes Deepdrivemd greatly advanced Working with Princeton Gordon Bell 2 billion paper Argonne National Laboratory Clear plans
Candle
Paper creates a surrogate howto &amp;ndash; GCF forgets this</description></item><item><title>Web Site</title><link>/blog/2021/02/09/web-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/09/web-site/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the the SBI Web Site and GitHub repositories have been created
Screen shot of the web Site.</description></item><item><title>Release 0</title><link>/blog/2021/02/07/release-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/07/release-0/</guid><description>More informatio nwill be here soon &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes 01-20-2021</title><link>/docs/notes/2021-01-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notes/2021-01-20/</guid><description>**Indiana University **
Report SBI-Meeting-IU-Jan20-2021
University of Tennessee Knoxville
Report SBI @ UTK 2k21
Deborah Penchoff joining the team
UTK Schema
MLFlow &amp;ndash; reproducibility
Is training repeatable
Need to have a group on this
UTK have their own surrogates science and performance
Storage
Uq
Hardware
Rutgers
**Report **SBI-Rutgers Jan 20-2021
Performance of surrogates
What does it mean
Gordon bell prizes
Deepdrivemd greatly advanced
Working with Princeton Gordon Bell
2 billion paper</description></item><item><title>PtychoNN: deep learning network for ptychographic imaging that predicts sample amplitude and phase from diffraction data.</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ptychonn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ptychonn/</guid><description>Metadata Model ptychonn.json
Datasets ptychonn_20191008_39.json
PtychoNN, uses a deep convolutional neural network to predict realspace structure and phase from far-field diffraction data. It recovers high fidelity amplitude and phase contrast images of a real sample hundreds of times faster than current ptychography reconstruction packages and reduces sampling requirements 1
References Mathew J. Cherukara, Tao Zhou, Youssef Nashed, Pablo Enfedaque, Alex Hexemer, Ross J. Harder, Martin V. Holt; AI-enabled high-resolution scanning coherent diffraction imaging.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>