<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Surrogates on SBI-FAIR</title><link>/docs/surrogates/</link><description>Recent content in Surrogates on SBI-FAIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/docs/surrogates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AutoPhaseNN: unsupervised physics-aware deep learning of 3D nanoscale Bragg coherent diffraction imaging</title><link>/docs/surrogates/autophasenn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/autophasenn/</guid><description>Metadata Model autophasenn.json
Datasets autoPhaseNN_aicdi.json
Adapted from Yao, Y. et. al 1 under CC-BY 2
AutoPhaseNN 1, a physics-aware unsupervised deep convolutional neural network (CNN) that learns to solve the phase problem without ever being shown real space images of the sample amplitude or phase. By incorporating the physics of the X-ray scattering into the network design and training, AutoPhaseNN learns to predict both the amplitude and phase of the sample given the measured diffraction intensity alone.</description></item><item><title>Calorimeter surrogates</title><link>/docs/surrogates/calorimeter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/calorimeter/</guid><description>Overview The Kaggle calorimeter challenge uses generative AI to produce a surrogate for the Monte Carlo calculation of a calorimeter response to an incident particle (ATLAS data at LHC calculated with GEANT4). Variational Auto Encoders, GANs, Normalizing Flows, and Diffusion Models. We also have a surrogate using a Quantum Computer (DWAVE) annealer to generate random samples. We have identified four different surrogates that are available openly from Kaggle and later submissions.</description></item><item><title>Virtual tissue</title><link>/docs/surrogates/virtualtissue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/virtualtissue/</guid><description>Overview Neural networks (NNs) have been demonstrated to be a viable alternative to traditional direct numerical evaluation algorithms, with the potential to accelerate computational time by several orders of magnitude. In the present paper we study the use of encoder-decoder convolutional neural network (CNN) algorithms as surrogates for steady-state diffusion solvers. The construction of such surrogates requires the selection of an appropriate task, network architecture, training set structure and size, loss function, and training algorithm hyperparameters.</description></item><item><title>Cosmoflow</title><link>/docs/surrogates/cosmoflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/cosmoflow/</guid><description>Metadata Model cosmoflow.json
Datasets
cosmoUniverse_2019_05_4parE_tf_v2.json
cosmoUniverse_2019_05_4parE_tf_v2_mini.json
Overview This application is based on the original CosmoFlow paper presented at SC18 and continued by the ExaLearn project, and adopted as a benchmark in the MLPerf HPC suite. It involves training a 3D convolutional neural network on N-body cosmology simulation data to predict physical parameters of the universe. The reference implementation for MLPerf HPC v0.5 CosmoFlow uses TensorFlow with the Keras API and Horovod for data-parallel distributed training.</description></item><item><title>Fully ionized plasma fluid model closures</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ionized-plasma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ionized-plasma/</guid><description>Fully ionized plasma fluid model closures (Argonne):1 The closure problem in fluid modeling is a well-known challenge to modelers aiming to accurately describe their system of interest. Analytic formulations in a wide range of regimes exist but a practical, generalized fluid closure for magnetized plasmas remains an elusive goal. There are scenarios where complex physics prevents a simple closure being assumed, and the question as to what closure to employ has a non-trivial answer.</description></item><item><title>Ions in nanoconfinement</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ions-in-nanoconfinement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ions-in-nanoconfinement/</guid><description>Metadata Model nanoconfinement.json
Datasets nanoconfinement.json
This application 1 2 3 studies ionic structure in electrolyte solutions in nanochannels with planar uncharged surfaces and can use multiple molecular dynamics (MD) codes including LAMMPS 4 which run on HPC supercomputers with OpenMP and MPI parallelization.
A dense neural-net (NN) was used to learn 150 final state characteristics based on the input of 5 parameters with typical results shown in fig. 2(b) with the NN results for three important densities tracking well the MD simulation results for a wide range of unseen input system parameters.</description></item><item><title>Molecule docking</title><link>/docs/surrogates/molecule-docking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/molecule-docking/</guid><description>Molecule docking: Docking small molecules to a protein’s binding site is often one of the first steps for virtual screening 1. Although many open-source and commercial packages exist for docking, AI approaches can be equally powerful (and computationally more efficient) for docking studies 2. Utilizing advances in control from reinforcement learning (RL), Argonne researchers trained an agent to drive the docking of a rigid ligand into a flexible protein pocket. The RL agent treats the ligand as a rigid body to which it can move through affine transformations along the protein.</description></item><item><title>miniWeatherML</title><link>/docs/surrogates/miniweatherml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/miniweatherml/</guid><description>Metadata Model miniWeatherML.json
Datasets miniWeatherML.json
Overview MiniWeatherML is a playground for learning and developing Machine Learning (ML) surrogate models and workflows. It is based on a simplified weather model simulating flows such as supercells that are realistic enough to be challenging and simple enough for rapid prototyping in:
Data generation and curation Machine Learning model training ML model deployment and analysis End-to-end workflows 12
References https://github.com/mrnorman/miniWeatherML&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
https://github.com/mrnorman/miniWeatherML/wiki&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>OSMI</title><link>/docs/surrogates/osmi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/osmi/</guid><description>Overview We explore the relationship between certain network configurations and the performance of distributed Machine Learning systems. We build upon the Open Surrogate Model Inference (OSMI) Benchmark, a distributed inference benchmark for analyzing the performance of machine-learned surrogate models developed by Wes Brewer et. Al. We focus on analyzing distributed machine-learning systems, via machine-learned surrogate models, across varied hardware environments. By deploying the OSMI Benchmark on platforms like Rivanna HPC, WSL, and Ubuntu, we offer a comprehensive study of system performance under different configurations.</description></item><item><title>Particle dynamics</title><link>/docs/surrogates/particle-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/particle-dynamics/</guid><description>Recurrent Neural Nets as a Particle Dynamics Integrator
The second IU initial application shows a rather different type of surrogate and illustrates an SBI goal to collect benchmarks covering a range of surrogate designs. Molecular dynamics simulations rely on numerical integrators such as Verlet to solve Newton&amp;rsquo;s equations of motion. Using a sufficiently small time step to avoid discretization errors, Verlet integrators generate a trajectory of particle positions as solutions to the equations of motions.</description></item><item><title>Performance Surrogate</title><link>/docs/surrogates/performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/performance/</guid><description>Overview Please contact Piotre
References</description></item><item><title>PtychoNN: deep learning network for ptychographic imaging that predicts sample amplitude and phase from diffraction data.</title><link>/docs/surrogates/ptychonn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/surrogates/ptychonn/</guid><description>Metadata Model ptychonn.json
Datasets ptychonn_20191008_39.json
PtychoNN, uses a deep convolutional neural network to predict realspace structure and phase from far-field diffraction data. It recovers high fidelity amplitude and phase contrast images of a real sample hundreds of times faster than current ptychography reconstruction packages and reduces sampling requirements 1
References Mathew J. Cherukara, Tao Zhou, Youssef Nashed, Pablo Enfedaque, Alex Hexemer, Ross J. Harder, Martin V. Holt; AI-enabled high-resolution scanning coherent diffraction imaging.</description></item></channel></rss>