<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on SBI-FAIR</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on SBI-FAIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metadata Subgroup</title><link>/docs/subgroups/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/subgroups/metadata/</guid><description>This subgroup is lead but University of Tennessee, Knoxville.
Schema Development As part of the logging, reporting activities, this subgroup is tasked to create appropriate schema to follow the FAIR principles. Below is a general overview of the major hierarchy of data that needs to be recorded for reproducibility.
Hardware specifications Compute: CPUs, Accelerators Memory: caches, NUMA Network: on-node CPU and accelerator coherency, NIC and off-node switches Peripherals Storage: primary (SSD), secondary (HDD), tertiary (RAID/remote) Firmware: ID/release date Software stack Compiler: GCC, Clang, vendor AI framework: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, MxNet Tensor backend: JAX, TVM Runtime: JVM, OpenMP, CUDA Messaging API: MPI, NCCL, RCCL OS: Linux Container: Singularity, Docker, CharlieCloud Input data Data sets (version, size) Image: MNIST digits/fashion, CIFAR 10/100, ImageNet, VGG Language: Transformer Science: instrument, simulation Annotations Model data Release date, ID, repo/branch/tag/hash, URL Output data Performance rate: training, inference Power draw: training, inference Energy consumption Convergence: epochs Accuracy, recall</description></item><item><title>Team</title><link>/docs/team/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/team/team/</guid><description> Geoffrey Fox, Indiana University (Principal Investigator) Vikram Jadhao, Indiana University (Co-Investigator) Gregor von Laszewski, Indiana University (Co-Investigator), laszewski@gmail.com, https://laszewski.github.io Rick Stevens, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Peter Beckman, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Kamil Iskra, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Min Si, Argonne National Laboratory (Co-Investigator) Jack Dongarra, University of Tennessee, Knoxville (Co-Investigator) Piotr Luszczek, University of Tennessee, Knoxville (Co-Investigator) Shantenu Jha, Rutgers University (Co-Investigator)</description></item></channel></rss>